sentence_id,article_id,article_text,published_time,sentiment,NER,topic_id,topic_representation
000-000,000," Musicians perform during a Mid-Autumn Festival themed event at the China Cultural Center in Tel Aviv, Israel, Sept. 27, 2023.",2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1), 'China Cultural Center': ('LOC', 1), 'Tel Aviv': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
000-001,000,Various celebrations are held across the world with the approaching of Mid-Autumn Festival.,2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
000-002,000,"(Xinhua/Chen Junqing) Actors perform at a gala celebrating the Mid-Autumn Festival in Hanoi, Vietnam, Sept. 20, 2023.",2023-09-29,positive,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Chen Junqing': ('PER', 1), 'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1), 'Hanoi': ('LOC', 1), 'Vietnam': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
000-003,000,Various celebrations are held across the world with the approaching of Mid-Autumn Festival.,2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
000-004,000,"(Xinhua/Hu Jiali) People taste mooncakes during a Mid-Autumn Festival themed event at the China Cultural Center in Tel Aviv, Israel, Sept. 27, 2023.",2023-09-29,positive,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Jiali': ('ORG', 1), 'Hu': ('PER', 1), 'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1), 'China Cultural Center': ('LOC', 1), 'Tel Aviv': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
000-005,000,Various celebrations are held across the world with the approaching of Mid-Autumn Festival.,2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
000-006,000,(Xinhua/Chen Junqing) ,2023-09-29,neutral,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Chen Junqing': ('PER', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
000-007,000,"A woman takes photos of mooncakes during a Mid-Autumn Festival themed event at the China Cultural Center in Tel Aviv, Israel, Sept. 27, 2023.",2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1), 'China Cultural Center': ('LOC', 1), 'Tel Aviv': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
000-008,000,Various celebrations are held across the world with the approaching of Mid-Autumn Festival.,2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
000-009,000,(Xinhua/Chen Junqing) ,2023-09-29,neutral,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Chen Junqing': ('PER', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
000-010,000,"A person practices China calligraphy during an event celebrating the Mid-Autumn Festival held by the Confucius Institute at the University of Latvia in Riga, Latvia, Sept. 25, 2023.",2023-09-29,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Riga': ('LOC', 1), 'Latvia': ('LOC', 1), 'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1), 'Confucius Institute': ('ORG', 1), 'University of Latvia': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
000-011,000,Various celebrations are held across the world with the approaching of Mid-Autumn Festival.,2023-09-29,positive,"{'Mid - Autumn Festival': ('MISC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
000-012,000,(Photo by Janis/Xinhua),2023-09-29,neutral,"{'Janis': ('ORG', 1), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
001-000,001," 

Saudi Arabia ambassador to Palestine Naif bin Bandar Al - Sudairi-Sudairi speaks during a joint press conference at the Palestine foreign ministry headquarters in the West Bank city of Ramallah, on Sept. 26, 2023.(Photo: Xinhua) 



 ",2023-09-27,neutral,"{'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'West Bank': ('LOC', 1), 'Ramallah': ('LOC', 1), 'Naif bin Bandar Al - Sudairi': ('PER', 2), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-001,001,"The first Saudi Arabia ambassador to Palestine Naif bin Bandar Al - Sudairi-Sudairi arrived in the West Bank on Tuesday, the official Palestine news agency WAFA reported.",2023-09-27,neutral,"{'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'West Bank': ('LOC', 1), 'Naif bin Bandar Al - Sudairi': ('PER', 2), 'WAFA': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-002,001,"Leading an official delegation, Al-Sudairi, the non-resident ambassador to Palestine and non-resident consul general in Jerusalem, presented his credentials to Palestine President Mahmoud Abbas at the presidency headquarters in Ramallah, it said.",2023-09-27,neutral,"{'Al - Sudairi': ('PER', 1), 'Mahmoud Abbas': ('PER', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Jerusalem': ('LOC', 1), 'Ramallah': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-003,001,Al-Sudairi's arrival comes amid Israel's efforts to normalize relations with Saudi Arabia.,2023-09-27,neutral,"{'Al - Sudairi': ('PER', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-004,001,"During their meeting, Abbas welcomed Al-Sudairi and said his visit to Palestine and his appointment as Saudi Arabia ambassador to the Palestine would contribute to ""strengthening the strong fraternal relations that bind the two countries and the two brotherly peoples.",2023-09-27,positive,"{'Abbas': ('PER', 1), 'Al - Sudairi': ('PER', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-005,001,"""The Saudi Arabia ambassador said he hoped that his visit would be ""a successful beginning for strengthening relations in all fields,"" stressing his country's firm and supportive positions for the Palestine people and their just cause.",2023-09-27,positive,"{'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-006,001,"Earlier in the day, Al-Sudairi told reporters in a statement that ""the Saudi Arabia Peace Initiative is the basic point in any upcoming agreement,"" after being asked about the fate of the initiative in the event of reaching a normalization deal between Saudi Arabia and Israel.",2023-09-27,positive,"{'Al - Sudairi': ('PER', 1), 'Saudi Arabia Peace Initiative': ('MISC', 1), 'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-007,001,The Saudi Arabia Peace Initiative was launched in 2002 after it was drafted by Saudi Arabia and adopted by the Saudi Arabia League.,2023-09-27,positive,"{'Saudi Arabia Peace Initiative': ('MISC', 1), 'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Saudi Arabia League': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-008,001,"The initiative calls for an end to the conflict between Israel and Palestine and the normalization of relations between Israel and Saudi Arabia states, in exchange for an Israel withdrawal from the areas it gained since 1967 and proper settlement to the issue of Palestine refugees.",2023-09-27,positive,"{'Israel': ('LOC', 3), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
001-009,001,"The Palestine demanded the establishment of an independent state alongside Israel in all of the Palestine territories occupied by Israel in 1967, including the entire West Bank and the Gaza, with Jerusalem as its capital.",2023-09-27,negative,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Israel': ('LOC', 2), 'West Bank': ('LOC', 1), 'Gaza': ('LOC', 1), 'Jerusalem': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
001-010,001,The Saudi Arabia ambassador also confirmed that his country intends to open a consulate in Jerusalem soon.,2023-09-27,neutral,"{'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Jerusalem': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-000,002," The China government released a white paper on Tuesday to introduce the theoretical base, practice and development of a global community of shared future, as by presenting China's vision of the course of human development, it counters the hegemonic thinking of certain countries that seek supremacy. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 2)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-001,002,"The white paper, titled ""A Global Community of Shared Future: China's Proposals and Actions,"" introduced the background for China to raise the concept of a global community of shared future as the world is undergoing changes on a scale unseen in a century with various problems posing unprecedented challenges for human society.",2023-09-26,positive,"{'Global': ('MISC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 2)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-002,002,"The zero-sum game is doomed to fail, the white paper said.",2023-09-26,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-003,002,"But certain countries still cling to this mindset, blindly pursuing absolute security and monopolistic advantages, which will do nothing for their development in the long run but create a major threat to the world. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-004,002,"It is increasingly obvious that the obsession with superior strength, and the zero-sum mentality are in conflict with the needs of our times, the white paper said, pointing out that the new era calls for new ideas. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-005,002,"To build a global community of shared future is to pursue openness, inclusiveness, mutual benefit, equity and justice, the white paper said.",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-006,002,The goal is not to replace one system or civilization with another.,2023-09-26,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-007,002,"Instead, it is about countries with different social systems, ideologies, histories, shared rights, and shared responsibilities in global affairs. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-008,002,The vision of a global community of shared future stands on the right side of history and on the side of human progress.,2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-009,002,"It introduces a new approach for international relations, provides new ideas for global governance, opens up new prospects for international exchanges and draws a new blueprint for a better world, according to the white paper. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-010,002,"Such important vision transcends outdated mindsets such as zero-sum game, power politics, and Cold War confrontations.",2023-09-26,negative,"{'Cold War': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-011,002,"It has become the overall goal of China's major-country diplomacy in the new era, and a great banner that leads the trend of the times and the direction of human progress. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-012,002,The concept of a global community of shared future has deep roots in China's profound cultural heritage and its unique experience of modernization.,2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-013,002,"It carries forward the diplomatic traditions of China and draws on the outstanding achievements of all other civilizations, the white paper said.",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-014,002,"It also manifests China's time-honored historical traditions, distinct characteristics of the times, and a wealth of humanistic values.  ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-015,002,"The white paper also pointed out the direction and plan to build a global community of shared future including pressing ahead with a new type of economic globalization in which countries need to pursue a policy of openness and explicitly oppose protectionism, the erection of fences and barriers, unilateral sanctions, and maximum-pressure tactics, so as to connect economies and jointly build an open world economy. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-016,002,"Some countries are seeking to decouple from China, enclosing themselves in ""small yards, high fences,"" which will ultimately only backfire, the white paper said.",2023-09-26,neutral,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-017,002,"Also, some people overstate the need to ""reduce dependence"" and ""de-risk,"" which is essentially creating new risks. ",2023-09-26,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-018,002,"The direction and the plan also include following a peaceful development plan, fostering a new type of international relations, practicing true multilateralism and promoting the common values of humanity. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-019,002,"Over the past decade, China has contributed its strength to building a global community of shared future with firm conviction and solid actions. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-020,002,"For instance, by July 2023, more than three-quarters of countries in the world and over 30 international organizations had signed agreements on Belt and Road cooperation with China.",2023-09-26,positive,"{'Belt': ('MISC', 1), 'Road': ('MISC', 1), 'and': ('ORG', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-021,002,The BRI originated in China but the opportunities and achievements it creates belong to the whole world.,2023-09-26,positive,"{'BRI': ('ORG', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-022,002,"It's an initiative for economic cooperation, not for geopolitical or military alliances, and it's open and inclusive process that neither targets nor excludes any party, the white paper said. ",2023-09-26,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-023,002,"Among those BRI projects, for example, the China-Laos Railway began operation on December 3, 2021, with 167 tunnels and 301 bridges built in 11 years along its total length of 1,035 kilometers.",2023-09-26,neutral,"{'BRI': ('MISC', 1), 'China - Laos Railway': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-024,002,"The railway construction created more than 110,000 local jobs, and helped build about 2,000 kilometers of roads and canals for villages along the railway, benefiting local people. ",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-025,002,"Besides the BRI, the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative and Global Civilization Initiative have evolved into a crucial cornerstone for building a global community of shared future, offering China's solutions to major challenges pertaining to peace and development for humanity. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'BRI': ('ORG', 1), 'Global Development Initiative': ('ORG', 1), 'Global Security Initiative': ('ORG', 1), 'Global Civilization Initiative': ('ORG', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-026,002,"Facing constant flare-ups of hotspot issues, China has been committed to fulfilling its role as a responsible major country, pushing for the resolution of international and regional flashpoints, such as the Korean Peninsula, Palestine, the Iran nuclear issue, Syria and Afghanistan, the white paper said. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Korean Peninsula': ('LOC', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Iran': ('LOC', 1), 'Syria': ('LOC', 1), 'Afghanistan': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-027,002,"On the Ukraine issue, China has actively promoted talks for peace, put forth four points, four things that the international community should do together and three observations, and released China's position on the political settlement of the Ukraine crisis and has dispatched the special representative of the China government on Eurasian affairs to engage in extensive interactions and exchanges with stakeholders on the political settlement of the Ukraine crisis. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'Ukraine': ('LOC', 3), 'China': ('LOC', 3), 'Eurasian': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-028,002,"Also, through the mediation of China, Saudi Arabia and Iran achieve historic reconciliation earlier this year, setting a fine example for countries in the region to resolve disputes and differences and achieve good neighborly relations through dialogue and consultation, and catalyzing a wave of reconciliation in the Middle East. ",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Iran': ('LOC', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-029,002,"China has also proposed a range of regional and bilateral initiatives on building communities of shared future and working with stakeholders to build consensus and expand cooperation, there by playing a constructive role in promoting regional peace and development.",2023-09-26,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-030,002,"It also boosts international cooperation in fields including fighting the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing disorder in cyberspace governance and dealing with the global climate challenge. ",2023-09-26,negative,"{'COVID - 19': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-031,002,"Over the past decade, the vision of a global community of shared future has gained broader support.",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
002-032,002,"More countries and people have come to the understanding that this vision serves the common interests of humanity, represents popular calls for peace, justice and progress, and can create the greatest synergy among all nations for building a better world, the white paper said.",2023-09-26,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
003-000,003," 

Ultra Orthodox Jews perform the Kaparot ceremony, where white chickens are slaughtered as a symbolic gesture of atonement ahead of Yom Kippur, the Jewish Day of Atonement, in Beit Shemesh, Israel, on Sept. 20, 2023.(Photo: Xinhua) 



An Ultra-Orthodox Jew holds a white chicken for the Kaparot ceremony, where white chickens are slaughtered as a symbolic gesture of atonement ahead of Yom Kippur, the Jewish Day of Atonement, in Bnei Brak, a suburb of Tel Aviv, Israel on Sept. 20, 2023.(Photo: Xinhua)",2023-09-22,neutral,"{'Ultra Orthodox Jews': ('MISC', 1), 'Kaparot': ('MISC', 2), 'Yom Kippur': ('MISC', 2), 'Jewish Day of Atonement': ('MISC', 2), 'Ultra - Orthodox Jew': ('MISC', 1), 'Beit Shemesh': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 2), 'Bnei Brak': ('LOC', 1), 'Tel Aviv': ('LOC', 1), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 2)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-000,004," 

A young Palestine patient receives treatment at the dialysis department of a hospital in Gaza, Sept. 20, 2023.",2023-09-21,neutral,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Gaza': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-001,004,"At least 1,100 Palestine kidney patients are facing an interruption of life-saving treatment due to a lack of medicines and medical equipment in the coastal enclave, the Hamas-run Health Ministry said on Wednesday(Photo: Xinhua) At least 1,100 Palestine kidney patients are facing an interruption of life-saving treatment due to a lack of medicines and medical equipment in the coastal enclave, the Hamas-run Health Ministry said on Wednesday.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Hamas': ('MISC', 2), 'Health Ministry': ('ORG', 2), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-002,004,"They include 38 children who are in danger of being denied access to dialysis sessions, Ashraf Abu Mahdi, director of the pharmacy department in the Health Ministry, said in a press conference held in Gaza.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Ashraf Abu Mahdi': ('PER', 1), 'Health Ministry': ('ORG', 1), 'Gaza': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-003,004,"""Patients with kidney failure are forced to live in difficult health conditions as medical supplies will be used up soon,"" Abu Mahdi added.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Abu Mahdi': ('PER', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-004,004,"Abu Mahdi indicated that stores run by the ministry in Gaza are short of related medical supplies, and the hospitals in Gaza provide 13,000 dialysis sessions for patients per month.",2023-09-21,neutral,"{'Abu Mahdi': ('PER', 1), 'Gaza': ('LOC', 2)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-005,004,"He accused Israel of ""banning the transport and shipment of medical supplies to the hospitals of the coastal enclave, putting the lives of thousands of kidney patients at risk.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
004-006,004,"""Israel has imposed a tight blockade on the Gaza, home to more than 2 million people, since the Hamas movement seized control of the enclave in 2007, widely blamed by Gazans for their poverty and hardship.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'Gaza': ('LOC', 2), 'Hamas': ('ORG', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
005-000,005,A US Marine Corps F-35B went down over South Carolina on Sunday after its pilot ejected mid-flight for reasons unknown.,2023-09-21,neutral,"{'US Marine Corps': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1), 'South Carolina': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-001,005,Why do F-35s seem so crash-prone?,2023-09-21,neutral,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-002,005,What’s wrong with them?,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-003,005,And what role does the waste and fraud in the US military-industrial complex play in creating such a Frankenstein’s monster of an aircraft?,2023-09-21,negative,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Frankenstein': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-004,005,Sputnik explores.,2023-09-21,neutral,"{'Sputnik': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
005-005,005,"Debris from the F-35B that went missing over South Carolina on September 17 was found in Williamsburg County, South Carolina, about two hours northeast of Joint Base Charleston on Monday following more than a day of frantic searching by the military.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1), 'South Carolina': ('LOC', 2), 'Williamsburg County': ('LOC', 1), 'Joint Base Charleston': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-006,005,An as yet unspecified “mishap” was blamed for the accident.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-007,005,The pilot escaped unscathed.,2023-09-21,neutral,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-008,005,"“The mishap is currently under investigation, and we are unable to provide additional details to preserve the integrity of the investigative process,” the Marine Corps said in a statement Monday.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Marine Corps': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-009,005,"The Marines ordered a two-day global pause in all aerial operations, with the errant F-35B becoming the third major aviation-related accident suffered by the military branch in less than two months.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Marines': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-010,005,"Air units will be discussing “fundamentals of safe flight operations, ground safety, maintenance and flight procedures, and maintaining combat readiness,” the Marine Corps said.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Marine Corps': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-011,005,"How Many F-35s Have Been Lost?Since it started being introduced into service with the Marines (2015), the US Air Force (2016), and the US Navy (2019) and began to be exported to foreign clients (starting with Israel in 2018), the F-35 has gained an unenviable reputation of being a costly, buggy, and crash-prone jet, with the F-35B that went down over South Carolina last week being at least the 11th Lightning II lost since 2018.On September 28, 2018, a US Marine Corps F-35B crashed during a flight near Marine Corps Air Station Beaufort in South Carolina, with a faulty fuel tube blamed for the incident.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 2), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 2), 'Lightning II': ('MISC', 1), 'US': ('MISC', 1), 'Marines': ('ORG', 1), 'US Air Force': ('ORG', 1), 'US Navy': ('ORG', 1), 'Marine Corps': ('ORG', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'South Carolina': ('LOC', 2), 'Marine Corps Air Station Beaufort': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-012,005,The pilot emerged unscathed.,2023-09-21,neutral,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-013,005,"On April 9, 2019, a Japanese Self- Defense Force F-35A went down off Honshu, Japan.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Japanese Self - Defense Force': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35A': ('MISC', 1), 'Honshu': ('LOC', 1), 'Japan': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-014,005,The pilot was killed after losing his bearings and suffering “special disorientation” mid-flight over the ocean.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-015,005,"On May 19, 2020, a US Air Force F-35A from the 58th Fighter Squadron crashed while performing a landing at Eglin Air Force Base in West Florida.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'US Air Force': ('ORG', 1), '58th Fighter Squadron': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35A': ('MISC', 1), 'Eglin Air Force Base': ('LOC', 1), 'West Florida': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-016,005,Pilot error (trying to land at excessive speed) and a mechanical defect related to a flight control glitch that left the plane’s tail unresponsive were blamed.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-017,005,The pilot survived.,2023-09-21,positive,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-018,005,"On September 29, 2020, a US Marine Corps F-35B was lost over Imperial County, California after colliding with a KC-130 tanker during midflight refueling.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'US': ('MISC', 1), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1), 'KC - 130': ('MISC', 1), 'Marine Corps': ('ORG', 1), 'Imperial County': ('LOC', 1), 'California': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-019,005,The tanker crew managed to bring their aircraft down for a hard landing.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-020,005,The F-35 pilot ejected successfully.,2023-09-21,positive,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-021,005,"On November 17, 2021, a British Royal Air Force F-35B plunged into the Mediterranean after its pilot ejected during routine operations.",2023-09-21,neutral,"{'British': ('MISC', 1), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1), 'Royal Air Force': ('ORG', 1), 'Mediterranean': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-022,005,That crash was ultimately blamed on a protective cover getting wedged into the plane’s engine intake.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-023,005,"On January 4, 2022, a South Korean Air Force F-35A suffering from issues with its onboard avionics carried out an emergency belly landing.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'South Korean': ('MISC', 1), 'F - 35A': ('MISC', 1), 'Air Force': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-024,005,Investigators blamed a bird striking the warplane’s landing gear mid-flight.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-025,005,The pilot emerged unharmed.,2023-09-21,neutral,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-026,005,"On January 24, 2022, a US Navy F-35C plunged into the South China Sea after making a hard landing on the USS Carl Vinson super carrier.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'US Navy': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35C': ('MISC', 1), 'Carl': ('MISC', 1), 'South China Sea': ('LOC', 1), 'USS': ('LOC', 1), 'Vinson': ('PER', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-027,005,The pilot and six sailors on the deck of the aircraft carrier were injured.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-028,005,A Navy investigation attributed the incident to pilot error.,2023-09-21,negative,"{'Navy': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-029,005,"On October 19, 2022, another F-35, this one from the US Air Force, crashed at Hill Air Force Base in Utah during a training mission.",2023-09-21,neutral,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 1), 'US Air Force': ('ORG', 1), 'Hill Air Force Base': ('LOC', 1), 'Utah': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-030,005,The pilot ejected safely.,2023-09-21,positive,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-031,005,It was later determined that turbulent air somehow confused the jet’s onboard avionics to the point where the aircraft became uncontrollable.,2023-09-21,negative,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-032,005,"On December 1, 2022, a Marine Corps F-35B collapsed on a military base in Japan after suffering a landing gear failure during training.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Marine Corps': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1), 'Japan': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-033,005,No one was injured.,2023-09-21,negative,{},1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
005-034,005,"Finally, on December 15, 2022, a US Navy F-35B crashed while attempting to perform a vertical landing at Naval Air Station Joint Reserve Base Fort Worth in Texas during testing of the jet’s systems.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'US Navy': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35B': ('MISC', 1), 'Naval Air Station Joint Reserve Base Fort Worth': ('LOC', 1), 'Texas': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-035,005,"A “harmonic resonance” issue related to the jet’s Pratt & Whitney F135 engine was blamed, with the Pentagon halting further F-35 deliveries by Lockheed until an investigation was concluded.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Pratt & Whitney': ('ORG', 1), 'Pentagon': ('ORG', 1), 'Lockheed': ('ORG', 1), 'F135': ('MISC', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-036,005,"What’s Wrong With the F-35?Nearly 17 years after the F-35’s first flight, and eight years after its adoption into service, the F-35 continues to maintain a troublingly long list of technical bugs affecting both hardware and software.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 3)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-037,005,"The aircraft, which has an astronomical total estimated purchase and sustainment price tag of over $1.7 trillion, and a per-plane cost of $70-$90 million, has faced years of harsh criticism from US officials, including former President Donald Trump at one point, who said the jet’s costs had spiraled “out of control.”At",2023-09-21,negative,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Donald Trump': ('PER', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-038,005,its heart,2023-09-21,positive,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
005-039,005,", the F-35 is the product of an idea that metastasized in the Pentagon after the end of the Cold War, envisioning an all-in-one fighter platform which could be used by every branch of the military, equipped with vertical take-off and landing capability, and carry out a broad array of missions using a variety of onboard weapons.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 1), 'Cold War': ('MISC', 1), 'Pentagon': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-040,005,"The do-it-all jet was supposed to replace nearly all of America’s fourth-gen fighter, strike, and ground attack aircraft, including the F-16 Falcon, the F/A-18 Hornet and Super Hornet, the AV-8B Harrier II, and others.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'America': ('LOC', 1), 'F - 16 Falcon': ('MISC', 1), 'F / A - 18 Hornet': ('MISC', 1), 'Super Hornet': ('MISC', 1), 'AV - 8B Harrier II': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-041,005,"The jet features just a single onboard engine – the aforementioned Pratt & Whitney F135, with engine-related troubles not only regularly referred to by watchdogs as a “leading driver” of the F-35’s problems remaining “mission capable,” but also making its operation over enemy territory or over the sea risky, since if something goes wrong, the plane doesn’t have a backup engine to limp home with.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'Pratt': ('MISC', 1), 'Whitney F135': ('MISC', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 1), '&': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-042,005,"Throughout its production cycle, the F-35 Lightning II has suffered a dizzying and seemingly endless list of technical problems, from neck-snapping ejection seats to problems, ironically, while operating in stormy weather.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'F - 35 Lightning II': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-043,005,"In its 2023 report, the congressional Government Accountability Office revealed that the F-35 program “continues to experience schedule delays, cost growth, and late deliveries,” with procurement costs jumping by $13.4 billion since 2019, and modernization behind schedule and over budget.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Government Accountability Office': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-044,005,"“As of January 2023, of the 821 open deficiencies, the program office characterized five of these as category 1",2023-09-21,neutral,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-045,005,"[i.e. critical issues which could jeopardize flight safety and security], and 816 as category 2, [i.e. those which could impede or constrain mission success].”In all, between December 2006 and 2023, the GAO has reported a whopping 277 category 1 and 2,467 category 2 deficiencies with the aircraft, among them serious issues like cabin over-pressurization, problems with the jets’ night vision systems, software bugs, radar issues, corrosion, ejection seats which could snap pilots’ necks, etc.Is a Culture of Largess to Blame?Sunday’s accident in South Carolina is the latest piece of F-35-related bad news for Lockheed Martin.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'GAO': ('ORG', 1), 'Lockheed Martin': ('ORG', 1), 'South Carolina': ('LOC', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-046,005,"In June, it was reported that the Pentagon had halted the delivery of any additional upgraded F-35s until major issues related to new Technology Refresh 3 (TR-3) hardware and weapons-related software were resolved.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Pentagon': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 1), 'Technology Reresh 3': ('MISC', 1), 'TR - 3': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-047,005,"DoD F-35 program director Mike Schmidt told Congress in March that the risk assessment related to the TR-3 hardware upgrade wouldn’t be finished until April 2024.Despite the delays and array of technical problems, the weapons giant has continued to rack up generous contracts related to F-35 procurement and production.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'DoD': ('ORG', 1), 'Congress': ('ORG', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 2), 'TR - 3': ('MISC', 1), 'Mike Schmidt': ('PER', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-048,005,"For example, in July, the US Navy ordered a $490 million package of equipment from Lockheed “to procure various material mod kits, special test/tooling equipment, as well as…product engineering” for already delivered, but defective planes.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'US Navy': ('ORG', 1), 'Lockheed “': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-049,005,"In August, Lockheed received another $606 million “fixed-price incentive (firm-target) undefinitized” contract “for long lead time materials, parts, components, and efforts to support of maintaining on-time production and delivery of 173 Lot 19 F-35 Joint Strike Fighter aircraft for Foreign Military Sales (FMS) customers and non-US Department of Defense (DOD) participants.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Lockheed': ('ORG', 1), 'Department of Defense': ('ORG', 1), 'DOD': ('ORG', 1), '19 F - 35 Joint Strike Fighter': ('MISC', 1), 'Military Sales': ('MISC', 1), 'non': ('MISC', 1), 'US': ('MISC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-050,005,”The,2023-09-21,neutral,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
005-051,005,"terms of the contracts seem to be the culprit behind the F-35’s soaring costs (and Lockheed’s soaring profits, despite delivery of defective products), with so-called “cost-plus” and “undefinitized” contracts effectively making any overruns the buyer’s problem – i.e. that of US taxpayers, and of citizens of any country unfortunate enough to pen contracts for the planes from Lockheed.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'F - 35': ('MISC', 1), 'Lockheed': ('ORG', 2), 'US': ('LOC', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-052,005,"What About America’s Competitors?The worst part about the F-35’s troublesome history seems to be that the F-35 has already become ""obsolete"" in the sense that many of the US and NATO’s competitors have obtained the ability to defeat them, with Russia and China gaining capabilities to track and target the jets going back to the mid-to-late 2010s.",2023-09-21,negative,"{'America': ('LOC', 1), 'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Russia': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 2), 'NATO': ('ORG', 1)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
005-053,005,"In April, Iran announced that its engineers had created advanced radar technologies to not only detect F-35s, but identify the radar signature of individual F-35 planes, enabling the Islamic Republic to plan defensive operations accordingly.",2023-09-21,positive,"{'Iran': ('LOC', 1), 'Islamic Republic': ('LOC', 1), 'F - 35': ('MISC', 2)}",3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
006-000,006,"Barely two months after an explosion in Louisiana, a train carrying toxic perchloric acid has exploded in a Nebraska rail yard on Thursday, prompting evacuation orders to be issued, as huge plumes are seen engulfing the city.",2023-09-15,positive,"{'Louisiana': ('LOC', 1), 'Nebraska': ('LOC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-001,006,Experts said the incident shows the US has been unable to take seriously and overcome major issues affecting public safety and the environment and ecology in the country.,2023-09-15,positive,"{'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
006-002,006,The incident happened on Union Pacific Railroad tracks in the city of North Platte.,2023-09-15,neutral,"{'Union Pacific Railroad': ('ORG', 1), 'North Platte': ('LOC', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-003,006,"North Platte Volunteer Fire Department announced that they would order those living in the area to evacuate due to the toxic smoke from the railroad, according to media reports.",2023-09-15,negative,"{'North Platte Volunteer Fire Department': ('ORG', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-004,006,"In a post on social media platforms, it said that ""Emergency evacuation for the area between splinter and front North of railroad track due fire at the railroad involving heavy toxic smoke.",2023-09-15,negative,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-005,006,"""In a statement to DailyMail.com, Union Pacific Railroad said that an explosion occurred inside a container which resulted in several railcars catching fire.",2023-09-15,negative,"{'DailyMail. com': ('ORG', 1), 'Union Pacific Railroad': ('ORG', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-006,006,"The railcar did not derail, the company said, and had been in the yard for several hours.",2023-09-15,positive,{},3,"['pilot', 'flight', 'aircraft', 'landing', 'jet', 'lockheed', 'navy', 'plane', 'crashed', 'issues']"
006-007,006,"Union Pacific said that one of the containers contained a hazardous chemical called perchloric acid, according to Daily Mail.",2023-09-15,neutral,"{'Union Pacific': ('ORG', 1), 'Daily Mail': ('ORG', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-008,006,"Perchloric is a hazardous material used in food, drugs and biocidal products, as well as explosives, according to the report.",2023-09-15,positive,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-009,006,"Two months ago, a fire at a Louisiana chemical plant triggered explosions that shook homes several miles away and sent flames and smoke billowing into the air in mid-July, prompting emergency officials to urge a few hundred nearby residents to shelter indoors for several hours and to turn off their air conditioners, the Associated Press reported.",2023-09-15,negative,"{'Louisiana': ('LOC', 1), 'Associated Press': ('ORG', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
006-010,006,Antiquated infrastructure and the outdated transportation were one factor.,2023-09-15,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
006-011,006,"Another was a flawed system of governance in the US transport industry, experts noted.",2023-09-15,negative,"{'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
006-013,006,"This shows that the US has been unable to take seriously and overcome serious and major issues affecting public safety and the environment and ecology in the country, Li said.",2023-09-15,positive,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Li': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
006-014,006,"""It must be said that this is a great irony to the self-proclaimed internal governance of the most advanced country in the world.",2023-09-15,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
006-015,006,"""Analysts said that the frequent occurrence of similar incidents shows that the error correction mechanism in the US has failed.",2023-09-15,negative,"{'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
006-016,006,"Apart from this, racism and the proliferation of guns are also clear examples of the failure of error correction mechanisms, experts noted.",2023-09-15,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
007-000,007," 

A rescuer of a Palestine rescue team prepares before departing for Libya, in the West Bank city of Ramallah, on Sept. 13, 2023.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1), 'West Bank': ('LOC', 1), 'Ramallah': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-001,007,Palestine on Wednesday sent a rescue team to eastern Libya where was struck by devastating floods.,2023-09-14,negative,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-002,007,"According to official data, at least 5,300 people are feared dead and over 10,000 more missing after the floods, which were triggered by Mediterranean storm Daniel and hit eastern Libya on Sunday.(Photo:",2023-09-14,negative,"{'Mediterranean': ('MISC', 1), 'Daniel': ('MISC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-003,007,"Xinhua) 



A rescuer of a Palestine rescue team prepares before departing for Libya, in the West Bank city of Ramallah, on Sept. 13, 2023.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1), 'West Bank': ('LOC', 1), 'Ramallah': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-004,007,Palestine on Wednesday sent a rescue team to eastern Libya where was struck by devastating floods.,2023-09-14,negative,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-005,007,"According to official data, at least 5,300 people are feared dead and over 10,000 more missing after the floods, which were triggered by Mediterranean storm Daniel and hit eastern Libya on Sunday.(Photo:",2023-09-14,negative,"{'Mediterranean': ('MISC', 1), 'Daniel': ('MISC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-006,007,Xinhua) Palestine on Wednesday sent a rescue team to eastern Libya where was struck by devastating floods.,2023-09-14,negative,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-007,007,"In a press statement sent to Xinhua, Ahmad al-Deek, political adviser at the Palestine Foreign Ministry, said the 37-member team is leaving for Libya and will join local and international teams in rescue operations and provide aid and assistance.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Foreign Ministry': ('ORG', 1), 'Ahmad al - Deek': ('PER', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-008,007,"In addition, al-Deek said that the floods have left at least 23 Palestine dead and dozens of others missing, adding that the ministry is consulting the Libyan authorities to follow up on the situation.",2023-09-14,negative,"{'al - Deek': ('PER', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Libyan': ('MISC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
007-009,007,"According to official data, at least 5,300 people are feared dead and over 10,000 more missing after the floods, which were triggered by Mediterranean storm Daniel and hit eastern Libya on Sunday.",2023-09-14,negative,"{'Mediterranean': ('MISC', 1), 'Daniel': ('MISC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
008-000,008," 

Displaced Palestine children wait to move from a shelter in Sidon to a center of the UN (UN) in Mount Lebanon Governorate, Lebaon, Sept. 12, 2023.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Sidon': ('LOC', 1), 'Mount Lebanon Governorate': ('LOC', 1), 'Lebaon': ('LOC', 1), 'UN': ('ORG', 2)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
008-001,008,"The latest round of armed clashes between members of the Fatah Movement and Islamic militants in the Ain Al-Helweh Palestine refugee camp broke out last Thursday evening and intensified in the following days.(Photo: Xinhua) 



 



Palestine from Ain Al-Helweh camp prepare to move from a shelter in Sidon to a center of the UN (UN) in Mount Lebanon Governorate, Lebaon, Sept. 12, 2023.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Fatah Movement': ('ORG', 1), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'UN': ('ORG', 2), 'Islamic': ('MISC', 1), 'Ain Al - Helweh Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Ain Al - Helweh': ('LOC', 1), 'Sidon': ('LOC', 1), 'Mount Lebanon Governorate': ('LOC', 1), 'Lebaon': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
008-002,008,The latest round of armed clashes between members of the Fatah Movement and Islamic militants in the Ain Al-Helweh Palestine refugee camp broke out last Thursday evening and intensified in the following days(Photo: Xinhua),2023-09-14,negative,"{'Fatah Movement': ('ORG', 1), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1), 'Islamic': ('MISC', 1), 'Ain Al - Helweh Palestine': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
009-000,009,"Chongqing, Sichuan, Shandong… Stelios Virvidakis expectantly plans his next China tour before a visit by the Global Times at his office in Athens, Greece. ",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'Chongqing': ('LOC', 1), 'Sichuan': ('LOC', 1), 'Shandong': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Athens': ('LOC', 1), 'Greece': ('LOC', 1), 'Stelios Virvidakis': ('PER', 1), 'Global Times': ('ORG', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
009-001,009,The University of Athens professor has grown far busier recently since he and four other Greek scholars launched the Center of China and Greek Ancient Civilizations in February.,2023-09-14,positive,"{'University of Athens': ('ORG', 1), 'Center of China and Greek Ancient Civilizations': ('ORG', 1), 'Greek': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-002,009,"Over the summer, the center has received two scholars from China who have given lectures on the history of China, and other visiting guests from places like Israel, who offered their views on China medicine and its history, and a lecturer from France with insights in China mathematics and how scholars in ancient China studied the living science.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 5), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'France': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-003,009,"""Students found them to be very interesting and greatly appreciated the lectures,"" Virvidakis told the Global Times.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Virvidakis': ('PER', 1), 'Global Times': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-004,009,"""Greece and China share so many similarities.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Greece': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-005,009,"So in my opinion, the horizon for our cooperation and exchanges is vast.",2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-006,009,There are endless possibilities which have not been explored.,2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-007,009,"""Mutual learning China President Xi Jinping replied to a letter from Virvidakis and four other Greek scholars earlier in 2023, extending congratulations over the founding of the Center of China and Greek Ancient Civilizations.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Xi Jinping': ('PER', 1), 'Virvidakis': ('PER', 1), 'Greek': ('MISC', 2), 'Center of China and': ('ORG', 1), 'Ancient Civilizations': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-008,009,"Hailing the long history of the China civilization and profound influence of the ancient Greek civilization, Xi Jinping said in the letter that more than 2,000 years ago, the two civilizations shone brightly on the two ends of the Eurasian continent, jointly making a fundamental contribution to the evolution of human civilization.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Greek': ('MISC', 1), 'Eurasian': ('MISC', 1), 'Xi Jinping': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-009,009,Greece's golden era produced many of its great philosophers and literary giants.,2023-09-14,positive,"{'Greece': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-010,009,"The era coincided with a period in China in which ""a hundred schools of thought contended with each other"" and flourished together.",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-011,009,"As early as the 4th century BC, China was known to the Greeks by a beautiful name:",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Greeks': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-012,009,Sērikḗ.,2023-09-14,neutral,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
009-013,009,"In the 16th century, Euclid's Elements was introduced into China, paving the way for scientific exchanges between China and the West.",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'Euclid': ('PER', 1), 'Elements': ('MISC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 2), 'West': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-014,009,The story of Prometheus narrated by Aeschylus was an inspiration to many China revolutionaries.,2023-09-14,positive,"{'Prometheus': ('PER', 1), 'Aeschylus': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-015,009,The Republic by Plato and Politics by Aristotle are also among the Greek classics known to have long made a name for themselves in China.,2023-09-14,neutral,"{'Republic': ('MISC', 1), 'Politics': ('MISC', 1), 'Greek': ('MISC', 1), 'Plato': ('PER', 1), 'Aristotle': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-016,009,"In the eyes of Virvidakis, China civilization has always been a culture that attracts people though the language is difficult.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Virvidakis': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-017,009,"However, China art, China painting, China poetry, especially love poems, even detective stories about China, are incredibly fascinating.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 4)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-018,009,"China director Zhang Yimou, and movies like Farewell My Concubine and Raise the Red Lantern starring Gong Li, are also very popular.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Zhang Yimou': ('PER', 1), 'Gong Li': ('PER', 1), 'Farewell My Conbine': ('MISC', 1), 'Raise the Red Lantern': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-019,009,Greek archaeologists who are interested in China archeology want to know how China explores the past.,2023-09-14,positive,"{'Greek': ('MISC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 2)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-020,009,"In other art forms, the mythology and theater, ""we have tragedy, which is our own tradition.",2023-09-14,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-021,009,"You have China opera with music.""",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",2,"['xu', 'music', 'mainland', 'island', 'straits', 'taiwan', 'ocean', 'stage', 'singers', 'philippines']"
009-022,009,"Actors and artists always want to study similarities and look at the differences, which is also the commitment of the center to promoting exchanges and mutual learning between the two civilizations and promoting the development of civilizations in various countries. ",2023-09-14,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-023,009,"China also has this appeal because people in the West think ""it's very different, it's exotic, something strange, but then they realize that it's beautiful for them.""",2023-09-14,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'West': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-024,009,"So ""they find a lot of aspects that they have not thought about before in order to understand.",2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-025,009,"""

Tiantan, a UNESCO World Heritage Site built in 1420, in Beijing Photo: VCGPhilosophy, a way of life There is a feeling among some people in the West that the China system is different in some ways, said the professor.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Tiantan': ('LOC', 1), 'Beijing': ('LOC', 1), 'West': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'UNESCO World Heritage': ('MISC', 1), 'VCGP': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-026,009,"For instance,the EU and US systems place great emphasis on individual rights, but China takes a more holistic approach in which ""harmony, social harmony is more important in sovereign.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'EU': ('ORG', 1), 'US': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-027,009,"""""We are not exactly the same and there are also differences.",2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-028,009,"But I don't believe in the so-called clash of civilizations theory that the clash is very deep and we can't live together with our differences,"" he told the Global Times. ",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'Global Times': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-029,009,"""In fact we can live together and have peaceful exchanges.",2023-09-14,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-030,009,"As I said, I don't think there is any danger of Greece threatening China or China occupying Greece.",2023-09-14,negative,"{'Greece': ('LOC', 2), 'China': ('LOC', 2)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-031,009,"""In February, Virvidakis held a lecture at the center's launching ceremony, titled Philosophy is a Way of Life.",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'Virvidakis': ('PER', 1), 'Way of Life': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-032,009,"Philosophy is not just theory, he said, noting that in ancient Greece and China it didn't mean just making theories about the universe, nature, god, or much of the unknown world.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Greece': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-033,009,"""It told you how to 'organize' your life to feel happy and achieve harmony with others.",2023-09-14,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-034,009,""" West philosophy cannot be understood just by itself as there are also China and Indian schools of philosophy among others.",2023-09-14,neutral,"{'West': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Indian': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-035,009,"""It is easier to see some similarities in ideas between Confucius and Socrates or Confucius and Aristotle,"" said Virvidakis, explaining why he is so fond of China philosophy, especially Confucius thought. ",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Confucius': ('PER', 3), 'Socrates': ('PER', 1), 'Aristotle': ('PER', 1), 'Virvidakis': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-036,009,A simple question about what is a good life has a variety of answers in different philosophical theories.  ,2023-09-14,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-037,009,But studying philosophy is practical and a way of life.,2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-038,009,Modern people don't just derive happiness from materialism.,2023-09-14,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-039,009,They need art and other emotionally stirring elements in life.,2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-040,009,"In different parts and different cultures of the world,people can share similarities in emotion and sentiment.",2023-09-14,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-041,009,"Virvidakis said that one of the most important reasons for his involving in such studies and exchanges was because ""I'm interested and I want to learn more.",2023-09-14,positive,"{'Virvidakis': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-042,009,I'm a student too.,2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
009-043,009,"When you are a teacher in your whole life, you're going to be a student.""",2023-09-14,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-000,010,"The China Foreign Ministry on Wednesday issued the Proposal of the People's Republic of China on the Reform and Development of Global Governance, with China analysts saying this comprehensive and far-sighted document reflects China's ideas and stances over almost all hotspot issues worldwide, and that it is crucial for the building of a community with a shared future for mankind.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 3), ""People ' s Republic of China"": ('LOC', 4), 'Foreign Ministry': ('ORG', 1), 'Global': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-001,010,"The year 2023 marks the 10th anniversary of the proposal of the idea of a ""community with a shared future for mankind"" by China President Xi Jinping.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Xi Jinping': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-002,010,"Over the past decade, this concept has grown from an idea to action, and from a vision to reality, said the proposal, adding that China calls on the international community to act on true multilateralism, uphold the international system with the UN (UN) at its core, support the UN in playing a central role in international affairs, and further develop and improve the global governance system.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'UN': ('ORG', 3)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-003,010,"Detailing the proposal at a regular press briefing on Wednesday, Mao Ning, a spokesperson for the China Foreign Ministry, said the international community expects the UN to play an active role in international affairs and continuously reform and improve the global governance system.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'Mao Ning': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Foreign Ministry': ('ORG', 1), 'UN': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-004,010,"The proposal comprehensively elaborates China's stance and propositions on key areas of global governance such as peace, security, development, human rights and society, as well as on institutional reform, she said.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-005,010,"Experts held that in the document, China released its latest stances and proposals about the Ukraine crisis, the nuclear issues of Iran and the Korean Peninsula, the Afghanistan issue, the Palestine-Israel conflict, as well as the issues of Syria, Sudan, Libya and Yemen.",2023-09-13,negative,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Ukraine': ('LOC', 1), 'Iran': ('LOC', 1), 'Korean Peninsula': ('LOC', 1), 'Afghanistan': ('LOC', 1), 'Palestine': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'Syria': ('LOC', 1), 'Sudan': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1), 'Yemen': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-006,010,"These stances are different from the US and some of its West allies, but much closer and similar to those of developing countries.",2023-09-13,neutral,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'West': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-007,010,"This proves that China will firmly stand with the justice and fairness upheld by the majority of the international community, rather than submit to hegemony.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-008,010,"On the Ukraine crisis, the document said: ""No one gains from conflicts and wars.",2023-09-13,negative,"{'Ukraine': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-009,010,"Imposing sanctions, exerting pressure, or adding fuel to the fire will only escalate the situation.",2023-09-13,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-010,010,"It is important to maintain mutual respect, abandon the Cold War mentality, stop ganging up to stoke camp-based confrontation, and work to build a balanced, effective and sustainable EU security architecture.",2023-09-13,negative,"{'Cold War': ('MISC', 1), 'EU': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-011,010,"""On",2023-09-13,neutral,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
010-012,010,"the Korean Peninsula nuclear crisis, the document said: ""Given the current situation, parties concerned need to remain calm and restrained, work to ease the situation and make efforts to create conditions for the resumption of dialogue, rather than insisting on sanctions and pressuring, which would only aggravate problems and escalate tensions.""Li",2023-09-13,negative,"{'Korean Peninsula': ('LOC', 1), 'Li': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-013,010,"Haidong, a professor at the China Foreign Affairs University, told the Global Times on Wednesday that ""currently, global governance faces huge challenges of turbulence, splits and confrontation, and in order to ensure security, stability and sustainable prosperity, we need positive, effective and well-accepted ideas for global governance and ensure they are implemented.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'Haidong': ('PER', 1), 'China Foreign Affairs University': ('ORG', 1), 'Global Times': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-014,010,This proposal is truly needed under the current situation.,2023-09-13,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-015,010,"""The thinking of the US and the West on global governance is outdated and getting increasingly dysfunctional, and the ongoing turbulence around the globe is proof.",2023-09-13,neutral,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'West': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-016,010,"The old West-dominated rules and ideas are based on unfairness, bullying and plundering against developing countries, and these have brought huge risks to the world, and created splits and confrontations, Li noted.  ",2023-09-13,negative,"{'West': ('MISC', 1), 'Li': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-017,010,"""China's idea for global governance is made to counter the unfairness and imbalances,"" Li said. ",2023-09-13,neutral,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Li': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-018,010,"On the Palestine-Israel issue, the document said: ""It is important to keep to the right direction of peace talks, respect the historical status quo of the holy sites in Jerusalem, refrain from making radical and provocative comments and moves, promote the hosting of an international peace conference with wider participation, higher authority and greater influence, create conditions for the resumption of peace talks, and make concrete efforts to help the two states of Palestine and Israel to coexist peacefully.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'Palestine': ('LOC', 2), 'Israel': ('LOC', 2), 'Jerusalem': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-019,010,"""China believes that regional hot spots such as the Iran nuclear issue and the issues of Syria, Sudan, Libya and Yemen need to be resolved through political means.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Iran': ('LOC', 1), 'Syria': ('LOC', 1), 'Sudan': ('LOC', 1), 'Libya': ('LOC', 1), 'Yemen': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-020,010,"China supports Middle East countries in independently exploring development paths, resolving regional security issues through solidarity and coordination, and maintaining lasting peace and security in the region, said the proposal.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-021,010,"Wang Yiwei, director of the Institute of International Affairs at the Renmin University of China, told the Global Times that the document is not only covering the ongoing hotspot issues and long-standing geopolitical crises, but also eyes the future.",2023-09-13,neutral,"{'Wang Yiwei': ('PER', 1), 'Institute of International Affairs': ('ORG', 1), 'Renmin University of China': ('ORG', 1), 'Global Times': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-022,010,"""The deep sea, polar regions, outer space, cyberspace and digital technology and artificial intelligence (AI) have become the new frontiers of global governance.",2023-09-13,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-023,010,"Faced with the new circumstances, new areas and new challenges, we need to follow the principles of peace, development, inclusiveness and shared governance, and take active steps to keep the rules governing new frontiers up to date with the times and fully reflective of developing countries' opinions, interests and aspirations.",2023-09-13,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-024,010,"The rights to participation, stating their views, and decision-making of developing countries should be fully safeguarded,"" said the proposal.",2023-09-13,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-025,010,"The international community should commit to upholding a cyberspace featuring peace, security, openness and cooperation, and oppose the camp-based division, militarization and fragmentation of cyberspace, the document said.",2023-09-13,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-026,010,"""No party should overstretch the concept of national security, or unscrupulously deprive another country of its legitimate right to development.",2023-09-13,positive,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-027,010,"Advantage in cyber technologies should not be used to spread aggressive cyber technologies, or turn cyberspace into a new battleground for geopolitical competition,"" the proposal reads.",2023-09-13,negative,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-028,010,"In these ""new frontiers,"" the UN system has yet to cover them all with sophisticated rules, so it is important for China to present its stance, to stress that the new frontiers should not become arenas for major power competition and should not be weaponized and militarized.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'UN': ('ORG', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
010-029,010,"They should be shared by the whole humanity, and while now some countries are unable to enter these new frontiers like outer space, the countries with advantages should preserve and safeguard their rights, Wang noted.",2023-09-13,positive,"{'Wang': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
011-000,011," 

 



Workers make shofars at a factory in Tel Aviv, Israel, on Sept. 10, 2023.",2023-09-12,neutral,"{'Tel Aviv': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
011-001,011,"Jews blow the traditional ""shofar"" or ram's horn while praying in synagogues during the holiday of Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish New Year.(Photo: Xinhua)",2023-09-12,positive,"{'Jews': ('MISC', 1), 'Rosh Hashanah': ('MISC', 1), 'Jewish New Year': ('MISC', 1), 'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
012-000,012," 

 

 

Participants pose for photos during a dragon boat race in Akko, Israel, on Sept. 8, 2023.",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'Akko': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
012-001,012,"A dragon boat race was held in northern Israel on Friday, with hundreds of paddlers from 17 teams nationwide competing in the Mediterranean.",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'Mediterranean': ('LOC', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
012-002,012,Photo:,2023-09-10,neutral,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
012-003,012,"Xinhua 

",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'Xinhua': ('ORG', 1)}",1,"['israel', 'palestine', 'lebanon', 'aviv', 'gaza', 'city', 'injured', 'bank', 'border', 'soldiers']"
013-000,013,"To celebrate the 10th anniversary of the BRI (BRI), the China Post recently issued a commemorative stamp inspired by the country's commitment to building a global community of shared future.",2023-09-10,positive,"{'BRI': ('MISC', 2), 'China Post': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-001,013,"The stamp is printed with ""The 10th Anniversary of the BRI"" in China and English.",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'BRI': ('MISC', 1), 'English': ('MISC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-002,013,"A golden number 10 is set in the center of the stamp, while the background abstractly combines the Earth's meridians and parallels, symbolizing the bright future of building a community of shared future for mankind through the BRI.",2023-09-10,positive,"{'Earth': ('LOC', 1), 'BRI': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-003,013,The golden bridge below the number is an art installation - Golden Bridge on the Silk Road by China artist Shu Yong. ,2023-09-10,positive,"{'Golden Bridge on': ('MISC', 1), 'Silk Road': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Shu Yong': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-004,013,"Based on the ancient Zhaozhou Bridge in North China's Hebei Province, the installation work conveys a message of a global community of shared future.",2023-09-10,positive,"{'Zhaozhou Bridge': ('LOC', 1), 'North China': ('LOC', 1), 'Hebei Province': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-005,013,It has been widely regarded as a cultural symbol of the BRI.,2023-09-10,neutral,"{'BRI': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-006,013,"It has been a core art installation at high-level events like the Milan Expo in 2015 and the Belt and Road Forum in Beijing in 2017.""Stamps can be seen as a country's name card as well as a national symbol that tell China stories about the new era.",2023-09-10,positive,"{'Milan Expo': ('MISC', 1), 'Belt and Road Forum': ('ORG', 1), 'Beijing': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-007,013,"Being part of the design team meant very much to me personally and professionally,"" Shu told the Global Times. ",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'Shu': ('PER', 1), 'Global Times': ('ORG', 1)}",-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
013-008,013,"""Bridges hold a distinctive connotation in China culture.",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-009,013,It represents building a channel for connection and communication.,2023-09-10,neutral,{},0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-010,013,"Including the bridge in the stamp is not only an acknowledgment to my work, but also shows the essence of the BRI,"" Shu noted. ",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'BRI': ('ORG', 1), 'Shu': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-011,013,"Over the past decade, the BRI has followed the guiding principles of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, which led to the inspiration for the central number 10 being composed of various shipping, air traffic and logistics logos as well as flowers.",2023-09-10,positive,"{'BRI': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-012,013,"""The China-Laos Railway, the new Haifa port in Israel, the Jakarta-Bandung High-Speed Railway… So many examples come to our mind when we think about the connectivity projects that are delivering tangible benefits to local residents via the BRI,"" Shu explained.  ",2023-09-10,positive,"{'China - Laos Railway': ('ORG', 3), 'Jakarta - Bandung': ('ORG', 2), 'BRI': ('ORG', 1), 'Haifa': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'High': ('MISC', 1), 'Speed': ('MISC', 1), 'Shu': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-013,013,"As a saying goes, ""a single flower does not make a spring.""",2023-09-10,neutral,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
013-014,013,"Different flowers bloom for the unique cultures from different countries across the world, further elaborating on the flowers in the central number, he said.",2023-09-10,positive,{},-1,"['algeria', 'china', 'tourism', 'sarcophagus', 'wildfires', 'cemetery', 'hawaii', 'antiquities', 'gaza', 'festival']"
013-015,013,"""It expresses China's commitment to deepening mutual learning among civilizations for a shared bright future, as well as its goodwill for common prosperity and development of all countries in the world,"" Shu said.",2023-09-10,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Shu': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-016,013,The China Post plans to issue 7.05 million copies of the commemorative stamp at 1.2 yuan (16 cents) per stamp.,2023-09-10,neutral,"{'China Post': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
013-017,013,"In addition to the stamp, the China Post, Hongkong Post and Macao Post and Telecommunications are jointly presenting a stamp booklet containing stamps and stamp sheetlets to mark the BRI's 10th anniversary together.",2023-09-10,neutral,"{'China Post': ('ORG', 1), 'Hongkong Post': ('ORG', 1), 'Macao Post and Telecommunications': ('ORG', 1), 'BRI': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-000,014,"As the US announced its Middle East railway plan during the Group of 20 (G20) Summit over the weekend in India, China experts expressed doubts about its credibility and feasibility, saying that it is not the first time for Washington to make empty pledges to various countries and regions.",2023-09-09,negative,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1), 'India': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Washington': ('LOC', 1), 'Group of 20': ('MISC', 1), 'G20': ('MISC', 1), 'Summit': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-001,014,"The experts noted that the true purpose of the Joe Biden administration is trying to ""isolate China"" in the Middle East, a region where China cooperation with the region has constantly gained momentum in recent years.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Joe Biden': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 2), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-002,014,The comment followed an announcement by US President Joe Biden and India regarding a multinational railway and port deal linking the Middle East and South Asia.,2023-09-09,neutral,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'India': ('LOC', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1), 'South Asia': ('LOC', 1), 'Joe Biden': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-003,014,The announcement came on Saturday on the sidelines of the G20 Summit.,2023-09-09,neutral,"{'G20 Summit': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-004,014,"Joe Biden said it was a ""real big deal"" that would bridge ports across two continents and lead to a ""more stable, more prosperous and integrated Middle East,"" according to a Reuters report.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Joe Biden': ('PER', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1), 'Reuters': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-005,014,"The idea of the rail and port network initially emerged at the I2U2 Business Forum, launched in 2021 by the US, India, Israel and the UAE to discuss infrastructure projects in the Middle East.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'I2U2 Business': ('MISC', 1), 'Forum': ('MISC', 1), 'US': ('LOC', 1), 'India': ('LOC', 1), 'Israel': ('LOC', 1), 'UAE': ('LOC', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-006,014,Saudi Arabia joined the discussions later.,2023-09-09,neutral,"{'Saudi Arabia': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-008,014,"""It is not the first time that the US has been involved in a 'much said, little done' scenario,"" Zhou said.",2023-09-09,neutral,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Zhou': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-009,014,"During the Obama administration, then US secretary of state Hillary Clinton announced that the US would sponsor a ""New Silk Road"" that would emerge from Afghanistan to link the country with its neighbors to increase its economic potential, but the initiative never materialized.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Obama': ('PER', 1), 'Hillary Clinton': ('PER', 1), 'US': ('LOC', 2), 'Afghanistan': ('LOC', 1), 'New Silk Road': ('MISC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-010,014,"""The Joe Biden administration's Middle East infrastructure plan is an apparent effort to counter the China-proposed BRI (BRI), which is entering its 10th year in 2023 with brought fruitful projects to partnering countries and regions.",2023-09-09,neutral,"{'Joe Biden': ('PER', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('MISC', 1), 'BRI': ('MISC', 2)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-011,014,"The Joe Biden administration is again engaging in bloc politics in order to slow down China's development,"" Zhou said.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Joe Biden': ('PER', 1), 'Zhou': ('PER', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-013,014,China has been engaging with the Middle East through the BRI for years.,2023-09-09,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1), 'Middle East': ('LOC', 1), 'BRI': ('ORG', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-014,014,"Its peacemaker role in the Saudi Arabia-Iran detente is lauded by the international community, the countries in the region in particular, which has injected stability into the region.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Saudi': ('MISC', 1), 'Arabia': ('LOC', 1), 'Iran': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-015,014,"In areas such as infrastructure construction, cooperation between the Gulf countries and China has advanced significantly in recent years.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Gulf': ('LOC', 1), 'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-016,014,"""It is impossible for the US to create a hedge in the short term,"" Liu said.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'US': ('LOC', 1), 'Liu': ('PER', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-017,014,"Zhou described the US plan as ""more of a symbolic gesture.""",2023-09-09,neutral,"{'Zhou': ('PER', 1), 'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-018,014,"From a technical perspective, the US decision to focus on transport infrastructure, an area where it lacks expertise, in a bid to salvage its declining influence in the region, suggests that the highly touted plan is unlikely to be realized. ",2023-09-09,negative,"{'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-019,014,"""In terms of the technology and costs of building railways, no country in the world than China has a more prominent advantage.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'China': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-020,014,"What the Middle Eastern countries want from the US is not just a railway, but also security.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'Middle Eastern': ('MISC', 1), 'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
014-021,014,"However, the US has neither provided nor been able to bring security to the region; instead, it has complicated the security situation there.",2023-09-09,positive,"{'US': ('LOC', 1)}",0,"['china', 'countries', 'iran', 'global', 'saudi', 'arabia', 'cooperation', 'peace', 'nations', 'israel']"
